# Leo Kalshteyn

646-262-9470 | leo.kalshteyn@gmail.com | github: Gorgutzz | LinkedIn: leokalshteyn Website: leokalshteyn.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and various frontend based programming languages with a background in IT hardware installation. Broadly knowledgeable in the latest web technologies as well as principles and techniques in app development. Possess strong skills in conveying technical information and learning new concepts.

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

**Planet Database** - A javascript app that allows users to add exoplanets to known star systems in the galaxy.

GitHub | Demo

- Utilized PostgreSQL to store stars and planets.
- Leveraged RESTful APIs to display planetary/star systems to the frontend via the backend app.
- Utilized Rack CORS middleware for handling cross domain AJAX calls.

**Museum Manager** - A rails app that allows users to take the role of a curator where they can manage museum exhibits.

GitHub | Demo

- Leveraged OmniAuth to authenticate users via GitHub.
- Implemented bcrypt to hash passwords for additional security.
- Frontend leveraged the Bootstrap framework to create a responsive experience on the frontend.

**Book Collection** - A Sinatra app that allows users to register and create a library of their favorite books for reference.

GitHub | Demo

- Developed an app which allowed user registration and utilizes basic CRUD functionality of book records utilizing the Sinatra framework.
- Implemented ActiveRecord associations to develop a user friendly and secure experience.
- Used Shotgun Development Server gem to run app.

**Quiz Buzz** - A React app which prompts the user with true of false questions based on Computer Science.

GitHub | Demo

- Utilized React to create a single page application.
- Written in TypeScript to implement cleaner and more efficient testable code.

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript	HTML / CSS	Rails	PostgreSQL	Heroku	Node.js
React	Sass	Python	Webpack	Git	Blockchain
Redux	Ruby	MySQL	jQuery	Unix/Linux	WordPress

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

A. B. Modi Inc. - New York, NY

Bubble.io Developer

January 2022 – Present

+ Leverage expertise in using No code Apps to develop Web and Mobile Applications using the Bubble.io platform.

#### Counting Coral - New York, NY

Web Developer, Intern

June 2021- December 2021

- + Ported the Counting Coral website from Wix to the WordPress platform using the Divi framework.
- + Redesigned the Counting Coral website through collaboration with the founders, translation of stakeholder vision into achievable code, and drafting new web pages in WordPress.
- + Diagnosed issues with cross browser compatibility allowing for a seamless feel across browsers.

#### East Coast, LLC - New York, NY

Technician April 2016 - June 2020

+ Installed, configured, and provided on-site support for wired/wireless surveillance equipment, including Network Video Recorders (NVR), IP Cameras (IPC), Wi-Fi access points (AP) and associated network cabling.

# **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School - New York, NY

February 2020

+ Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program.

Hunter College - New York, NY

March 2017